with the exception of the goalie everyone's playing a position they've never played before
listen up you have 10 minutes left show us everything you've got are you freaking kidding
me this is hell
they've been playing in unfamiliar positions and they're still slaughtering us out there
they're just high school first years that's only a year above us we must be so far behind
how are we supposed to catch up to them in a year
we can't there's absolutely no way
i've been wondering the money where did shun get it how was he able to save up so much for me
you
It still hurts where Akutsu ran into me.
It's like he's stuffed with cement.
My legs are pretty spent, too.
No way! Thanks, Mom!
Now I can play soccer in junior high, too!
I guess I never realized how expensive cleats are.
Don't worry, Mom! I promise I'll pay you back someday!
I'm gonna be a world-class pro player when I grow up, and I'll buy you anything you want!
Pathetic, really.
I mean all the kids around you.
Damn it!
Is this it?
Am I done?
All because of that poser jerk?
Seems like all the candidates are just suddenly giving up.
I wonder what's going on.
It's not that the other team is too strong.
Telling them they're playing out of position was a stupid move.
That's shocking enough to throw anyone off their game.
What kind of deadbeat manager does that?
What are you doing, Kaneda?
Kaneda, hustle!
Kaneda, run!
Come on.
How'd he get the ball to stop right there as if he told it to?
This is incredibly uneven.
There's no way we're anywhere near their level.
They know exactly what they want to do, and they just do it.
I'm pathetic.
I've ruined it.
They don't need me.
I'm completely worthless.
Come on.
Corner kick!
I just want to go home and take a hot bath.
I'm over it.
Regular soccer with my friends at home is all I really need.
There's nothing for me out here.
You look like an awkward zombie.
I'm so done.
I tried.
I gave it everything I had.
So that's it.
Done.
You giving up?
What do you mean?
Giving up?
I quit.
Oh.
Hello to you, too.
I didn't make it.
It is what it is.
Okay, so what's your plan going forward?
Huh?
I'm still going to play soccer like I always have.
That's good.
Yeah, but I don't want to go pro.
I mean, it's overrated and no one near is fu-
Oh.
Heh heh.
Whoa, nice clearing!
Who said anything about giving up?
Average annual income for a J2 player.
I bet it's about the same as an office admin.
Hey, there's nothing wrong with being curious.
Besides, it's not likely he'll get signed, is it?
Likely?
Nah.
I guess he could, but the odds are pretty slim.
He's basically trying to enter the ideal soccer club.
They do have a few elite members and staff, but their top players all came through their youth program.
Then only the best get in?
Correct, and normally Ashito wouldn't stand a chance, but that's okay with you because you don't like to think about him leaving the nest.
Am I right?
I don't like either option, to be honest.
All he has to do is try his best and be true to himself till the very end.
Not today!
Ah, nice play!
I cleared that second corner kick to safety!
Way to go, Ashito!
Uh, is he cheering for himself?
Crap!
I can't think about anything other than this match.
It's not like me to get distracted.
If the other team's too strong for us to beat, I should just play my own game.
Man, that number 10 is pretty impressive.
He's still got the strength to run.
Eh?
Oh?
Huh?
it's not only about this one game
you've been doing great all day
don't give up
oh that's the old man's little sister
she seems really nice
this is it less than three minutes to go
come on guys you can do it
oh crap got it
Tachibana stay close to me
maybe we can break through down the wing behind them
seriously
Ashito Aoi is honestly not that good
he's tough though
and that makes others feel strong
well not everyone
maybe it's just me
I won't give up
not now
I've come this far
at the expense of my home team
there's no way
I'm giving up on their support
handball handball
foul
I'm perfect timing
oh man
what are you doing Yuma
fullback's a tough position
isn't it
hey Ashito Tachibana
oh
I got an idea
how about you let me do the free kick
hey Otomo
what's with you
hmm
you're like a totally different dude
before the game than during it
hmm
I get nervous before games
I always stress about what might happen
but once that whistle blows
I immediately calm down
and can focus for some strange reason
that's a pretty intense shift
how do you do it so fast
I never thought about it
is that weird
maybe because of how much I like playing the game
wow
we don't have much time left
my all-time favorite player said the game was always right there
whatever he was doing soccer was on his mind
best of luck
and remember a man is but a thinking read
that's right
I need to think
and think fast
time's running out
I need a final play
it's got to be memorable
and perfectly executed
stop freaking out
and just think
this one's going in
how high can that freak show jump
push up
let's go
oh great
owie
they're counter attacking
come on
I think we should
where'd you go
hey jerk
give me the ball
huh
no way
oh sonny
that should have been easy
did you forget how to one touch pass
seriously
what is up with this owie guy
he tracks back so fast
I swear
he was just standing in front of the goal a minute ago
right next to the kicker
he must have started running the moment I cleared the ball
only way he could have covered that distance
but even if that's what he did
something still doesn't add up
what made him run straight towards
how could he have possibly known the ball would wind up with him that many steps ahead
oh damn it
he finally caught up to him but
if they get the ball deep into our half
they'll run out of time
oh
where's this head
nakano
howie
you're still strong enough to run around like that
amazing
amazing I wish I could keep going too but I'm not as good as you and besides
I've lost my will to fight I'm sorry this is it for me damn it but if we can
just get one just one goal
wow he went out wide send it back they're gonna swarm you you idiot stay back
close in the other wing it actually got through number five they're attacking mid drifted right
did he go out there to cover for number eight while he's spacing out now's the moment shoot
close in
he's completely free
clear the ball if we do game over
close in
no what on earth is he doing here and how
I have to close in
now
ah
Perfect goal.
Soccer's all about what you do off the ball.
How you keep going when it's not at your feet.
That was a classic attack.
But he showed how it could be done with just three players, by pulling all the strings himself.
Ashito Aoi.
It sure is something.
Next person, please.
Owie.
You made it to the final interview, but the questions will be simple.
The worst thing you can do is overthink them.
Best to simply say whatever comes into your head.
So the youth team, what all did you think?
They're strong.
No, not just strong.
Aside from the last goal, I could barely do a thing.
I was shocked to hear they were playing out of position.
But it was more than that.
Something about them was frightening.
I've never thought about giving up on the field before.
Not in all my years of soccer.
But I did out there today.
Oh, what was the point of all that?
I mean, why'd you make them play out of position in the first place?
Did you really want to handicap them?
Sorry, you're asking me a question?
Uh, I guess.
If you must know, it was a training exercise.
They had plenty of warning.
I told them about a week ago that they'd be playing the youth club applicants.
And I expected them to crush you despite being assigned different positions.
I couldn't let you guys be the only ones feeling the heat.
But this past week, they've been thinking about it and talking about it at length together.
They've never had to spend so much time analyzing positions that weren't their own before.
Anyway, the real objective here was to find out more about the candidates.
Like, how do they react when they're backed into a corner?
Or how many surprises can pop up before they crumple?
How strong do you think you are mentally?
Mentally? Why?
Because it's the most important trait to have in J-Youth.
So get out.
Ask him about that one goal.
You ask him about that dumb goal.
All right.
The last goal.
What was your thought process leading up to it?
Honestly, I don't remember.
Hmm.
I don't know what happened.
Or how I pulled it off.
And remember, a man is but a thinking reed.
Oh, wait.
Hold on.
I'm not saying I zoned out.
I was thinking.
Or trying to.
I remember thinking I should go to the left.
But I don't remember exactly why.
Was there something you saw?
I don't know.
I guess.
I saw Otomo running toward the goal out of the corner of my eye.
And I felt like he knew exactly what I was trying to do.
Even though I still didn't have a clue at that point.
And then, I think, I closed in on the goal, just in case he missed.
Excellent.
He can verbalize it.
What else did you think about?
My mom and brother.
Huh?
It was my mom and my brother.
They kept me going.
The only reason I could score was because of them.
Up until today, I've only ever played soccer the way I wanted to.
I wanted to go pro, but I never considered what that actually means.
All I've done is cause trouble.
I owe them so much.
I have to pay them back for it.
The only way for me to do that is through soccer.
By going pro.
And, I realized how hard it would be after seeing all those guys so determined to make it.
Thanks for bringing me out here, old man.
No matter what happens, I'm grateful.
I know now that even if I don't make your team,
I'm gonna go pro.
Because I'm meant to.
Man, Hashito, you're something special.
You're the only candidate who actually scored against the youth team.
Ha, ha, ha.
I guess I did do that, didn't I?
See?
What did I tell you?
I'm totally getting signed.
I'm a freaking genius after all.
Ha, ha, ha.
So if you don't hear from them at all then,
you should just assume you didn't make it, right?
Home.
Hmm?
They did say it could take up to three weeks for them to decide.
You've still got some time.
And if you get in, then what?
Do you have a plan?
Are you ready to move to Tokyo?
Hmm?
All right.
I'll see you later, Shun.
I'm gonna head home and take a nap before my night shift.
Cool.
As for you, I'm giving you all a discount on the shaved ice,
so tell your dads to come have a drink later, m'kay?
K!
Not a word about me taking off for the tryouts in Tokyo
without running it by her first.
Something's not right here.
Ashito.
Huh?
I know you're pretending it doesn't matter,
but I think it does.
You've literally been losing sleep over it.
Yeah, sure.
Of course I care if I make it or not.
But what can I do?
I did my best and mentally prepared for the worst.
And then I think, what if I do get in?
There's no way I could move to Tokyo by myself.
I'm a mess.
Doesn't matter.
I hope I get picked.
I do.
Uh, Ashito, what's that thing sticking out of your pocket?
Is it a letter?
Oh, this?
I almost forgot about this one.
Don't read it till you're back in Ehime.
Promise me you won't!
Uh?
Dude, are you for real?
From the manager's sister?
Did she seriously write you a love letter?
Of course not.
Don't be an idiot.
It doesn't make a lot of sense anyway.
Did she write you a meal plan?
Oh.
Is she trying to be a nutritionist or something?
I don't know.
I didn't ask her.
I mean, she did help me keep going through tryouts.
So I'm grateful to her for that.
Bro, you've been sitting on a valuable resource.
Call her.
She's the manager's sister.
She knows if you made it.
Hello?
Uh, Ashito.
Huh?
This came in the mail for you.
I was curious.
I'm sorry I opened it before you.
Congratulations.
Great, right?
I'm proud of you.
But I'm torn about soccer.
It's taking you away from me.
I'm proud of you.
Next time on Aowashi Orange Scenery.